Take the lab rat,
ネズミ匹
no,
違います
the roast chicken.
鶏を焼く
Take the roast chicken and locate
鶏の両側を焼く
the midpoint of the front line of the upper spine as the center line.
上背前線の中点を中線とする
Five millimeters to the left of the center line,
中央線から左へ5ミリのところ
we bluntly separate the subcutaneous tissue...
ふどうせいぶんり皮下組織
And paravertebral muscles.
椎間筋
How about that?
どうでしょう姉妹たち
A whole morning of experiments on lab rats
午前中のマウス実験
is not a waste of time, is it?
練習してないでしょ
Yes, it is.
むだに練習した
Can you say something I like to hear instead?
お姉さんの好きなことを言ってください。
Say,
あなたは
Gu Chen was doing great
顧晨は以前実験室で
in his previous lab,
よくやった
why did he suddenly transfer
なぜ突然
to your lab?
実験室はどこだ?
He said that he's more interested in
彼は杜専門家の研究方向を言った
Du Zhuanjia's research fields.
彼はもっと興味を持っている
It's but an excuse.
これはすべて口実だ
Gu Chen's GPA is 4.9.
顧晨の成績は4時9分だ
He'll be accepted by any lab
彼はどの実験室に行きたいですか。
if he applies, right?
彼は行けないよね
Right.
そうだ
Moreover,
もういい
if he's so interested in
彼は本当に杜先生の実験に対して
Prof. Du's experiments,
そんなに興味がある
why didn't he apply
彼が最初に
at the beginning?
どうして行かないの
Am I right?
そうですか
Yes.
はい
Yes, you are.
そうだ
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ?
Say,
あなたは
is there any possibility that Gu Chen is
朝のことを考えていると
into you?
あなたに興味があります
He knew that you are not happy
彼はあなたがショー宇河にいるのを見た
working at Xiao Yuhe's place,
楽しくない
so he discreetly and deliberately
だからこっそり
transferred here to lend you a hand.
こっちに来て手伝ってあげる
Be realistic.
いちばん上の姉
When I bought allergy medications
その時私は肖宇河に
and a jacket
アレルギー薬を買う
for Xiao Yuhe,
そしてコートの時
it was Gu Chen who kept me company.
朝を見て私と一緒に行ったのです
He knows that I have a crush on Xiao Yuhe.
彼は私がショー川が好きだと知っている
Then that's even more telling.
それはもっと問題だ
Previously,
前
he knew that you have a crush on someone,
彼はあなたに好きな人がいることを知っています
so he cannot do much
だから仕方ない
other than supporting you
背中にしか
silently from behind.
黙々と応援します
But now it's different.
でも今は違う
The situation has changed.
状況が変わる
Instead of supporting in silence,
彼は黙っていないことにした
he decides to step in.
身を挺して出る
In.
から出る
Li Meizi,
梅の実
look at me.
私を見て
I'm all hurt and broken.
もう傷だらけだ
Any teeny-weeny
もう少しだけ
trivial stuff
些細なこと
can be my last straw.
すぐにフリーズして再起動します
Just let me be,
やめてくれ
please.
いいですか
Hurry up and eat.
急いで食事をする
Then I'll head to the lab.
食事が終わったら実験室に行きました
They are a... a...
彼ら2人は配合している
a match made in heaven.
天仙配
OK, we've done messing around.
騒ぐか騒がないか
Let's dig in.
ご飯を食べてご飯を食べる
Look.
ほら
The clubs are full of handsome boys.
サークルにはイケメンがいっぱい
They are recruiting new members recently.
最近サークルで新入生を募集しています
We should drop by and have a look later.
後で行ってみましょう
Hurry and eat.
早く食べて早く食べて
Hello,
クラスメート人
can I interest you in the Ping Pong Club?
卓球部に来て調べてみましょう
A hit on the ball, and you'll be the best of all.
ピンポンパンは天下無双だ
Hello,
クラスメート人
can I interest you in the Street Dance Club?
ストリートダンス社について
I... I'll take a look at the Ping Pong Club.
私は卓球を見に行きました。
Then I'll take a look over there.
じゃ、あそこに行ってみます
Later.
歩いて行く
Chengcheng,
クリアー
you are interested in calligraphy?
書道に興味がありますね
I... I'm just browsing around.
私は勝手に見ていました
You are also trying to join a club?
あなたもサークルに来て
Yes, I'm still choosing.
ああまだ選んでる
Is there any possibility that Gu Chen's
朝のことを考えていると
into you?
あなたに興味があります
He knew that you are not happy
彼はあなたがショー宇河にいるのを見た
working at Xiao Yuhe's place,
楽しくない
so he discreetly and deliberately
だからこっそり
transferred here to lend you a hand.
こっちに来て手伝ってあげる
Then I suppose you have already
明日の宿題は
finished the physics assignment that's due tomorrow.
やり終えただろう
Have you picked a topic?
課題は決まったか
Not yet.
まだです
It's due tomorrow.
明日提出します
How about this.
そうでしょう
You hurry up and pick one today,
今日は早く選んで
and I'll ask the professor tomorrow
明日先生に言っておきます
to give our class one more day.
私たちのクラスはあさってに提出します。
Thank you, monitor.
ありがとう班長
I'll go and find Meizi, then.
では梅を探しに行きます
OK.
行きましょう
Are you alright?
あなたは大丈夫ですか
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Xixi.
西渓姐
Could you take a look at
ちょっと見てもらえませんか。
my design and see
私のこのデザイン
if there's something wrong with it?
何か問題があるのではないでしょうか
Your design is
これはあなたです
an experiment for long-term monitoring
マウス大脳ニューロン
of lab rats' brain neuronal activity.
長期モニタリングの実験
Electrodes are implanted for up to one year.
電極移植期間は1年に及ぶ
Now, you are using a
あなたが今使っているのは
Utah Electrode Array.
ユタアレイ電極
It will cause immune responses
この電極は注入時間が長くなった
when implanted for too long,
免疫反応が起こります
which will lead to failure.
失効を招く
In the end, the functioning time will only be a few months.
最後の有効期間は数ヶ月しか残っていません
You should change it into
あなたは1つに変えるべきです
nano-mesh electrodes.
ナノメッシュ電極
OK.
行
Thank you, Xixi.
ありがとう西渓姉さん
Wait, Xixi,
そうだ渓姐
do you have any time available in the next two days?
あなたはこの2,3日暇ですか。
I want to treat you to dinner.
私はあなたに食事をごちそうします。
You have time for dinner,
食事をする時間がある
but you don't have time for your thesis?
論文を書く時間はありませんか。
If you don't submit it tomorrow,
明日は出さない
you'll be doomed.
死んでやる
I will. I will.
交差
Thank you, Xixi.
ありがとう西渓姉さん
Xixi,
渓姐
why are today's chips all coriander flavored?
今日はどうして香菜味ばかりですか。
Who bought these?
これは誰が買ったのですか。
They were all purchased by Gu Chen.
これはすべて朝に買ったのです
By Gu Chen?
朝に買った
Xixi, Dongmao.
西渓先輩の東茂先輩
Both of you are here.
みんないるよ
Gu Chen.
顧晨
Do you also like
あなたも食べるのが好きです
coriander flavored chips?
パクチー味のポテトチップス
Didn't you
前回の先輩
give me a bag of coriander flavored chips last time?
あなたは私に一包みくれたのではありませんか。
I found it tasty.
味は悪くないと思います
So I bought some more.
また買ってきた
Right, Xixi.
そうだ先輩
How's your study
あなたの
on how to use steady-state visual evoked potentials (SSVEP)
ていじょうしかくゆうどうでんい
to locate retinopathy cells
網膜病変細胞の
coming along?
位置決めはどうなっていますか。
It's still processing.
それはまだ進んでいる
I'm going to study more about it
今夜家に帰るつもりだ
tonight.
さいけんきゅう
This flavor tastes awful.
この味はまずい
Fortunately,
まだですか
I didn't pay for it myself.
自分でお金を使って買った
What tastes so awful?
何を食べるのがこんなにまずいのか
Coriander flavored chips.
パクチー風味のポテトチップス
Coriander flavored?
パクチー味
Why are you eating
張西渓のものを食べなさい
Zhang Xixi's stuff?
何をする
It's not her purchase.
渓姉のものではありません
Gu Chen bought it.
朝に買った
There are plenty of these in the lounge.
ラウンジはいっぱい買ってきましたね
I can fetch one for you.
バッグを持ってきてあげましょう
No, I'm good.
私は食べません
Here, try one.
やってみよう
No.
食べない
Who bought it?
誰が買ったと言った?
Gu Chen.
朝のことを考えていますか。
This dog cafe
この犬カレー
is trending on social media.
しかし、ネット有名店は
It's very difficult to book a table.
本当にとても難しいです
But of course,
もちろんです
all our consumption
私たちの今日のすべての消費
will be paid for by Ms. Li.
すべて李総経理が勘定する
Cheers.
乾杯！
I want a snap too.
私も撮ります
I'm gonna post it on Moments.
私もモーメンツを送ります
This is delicious.
これはおいしい
Too sweet.
甘い
It's fine.
まあまあです
Good grief.
なんてことだ
Did you check your Moments?
モーメンツを見たか?
Who did Gu Chen
顧晨これは誰と
make the romantic gestures for?
空を隔てて愛を示している
It's not something he normally would do.
彼らしくないな
Take a look.
ほら
Let me see.
見てみろ
"Dragons should hide in clouds."
竜は雲の中に隠れるべきだ
I know this one.
それはわかってる
It's from The Scenery under Moon by Shen Congwen.
これは沈従文の月下の小景です
The next sentence is
次の文は
"You should hide in my heart."
あなたは心の中に隠すべきです
Gee.
なんてことだ
Gu Chen has a crush on someone.
朝を見て好きな人ができた
I should gossip about this.
ゴシップをするべきだ
How come I can't see this?
どうして見えないんだ?
How come you can't...
どう思う？
Gimme. Lemme see. Hurry.
見せてくれ!!
Why can't you see this post?
どうして持ってないの?
Can you all see it?
持ってる?
Yes, of course.
ありますよ
We all can see it.
全部あるよ
Let me think.
ちょっと考えさせて
No way.
まさか
You can't be the heroine
顧晨が言ったヒロイン
Gu Chen's talking about.
まさかあなたでしょう
You are his crush.
あなたは彼の心の上の人でしょう
He's too shy about it,
彼はきまりが悪い
so he blocked you on this post.
だからあなたを隠した
It's impossible.
まさか
Maybe Gu Chen
朝のことを考えていると彼ははっきり言えない
blocks me entirely.
モーメンツが私をブロックしている
Lemme see.
見せてくれ
See for yourself.
自分で見てみろ
It's just this one post that's hidden from you.
これだけはありません
Right?
そうですか
What do you think?
どう思う?
Does Gu Chen like Su Chengcheng?
朝を顧みて蘇澄澄が好きなのではないでしょうか。
Good for you, Chengcheng.
いいですね澄まして
I heard that Gu Chen
顧晨と聞いた
grew up in a wealthy family.
家の条件がいい
He bought his own house
高校の時
when he was in high school.
人が家を全部買ってしまった
I also think Gu Chen is a decent choice.
私もモーニングコールがいいと思います
He's more suitable for you than Xiao Yuhe.
彼はショー宇河より君に適している
See?
ほら
Even Bro Ying, who's always silent in discussions,
普段は話題に乗らない穎兄さん
spoke up.
みんな話した
What do you think?
どう思う？
But,
しかし
the person I have a crush on is not Gu Chen.
私の好きな人は朝ではありません
What did you say?
何て言った?
I mean we are just
私は私と顧晨と言った。
good friends.
親友だ
I'm pretty sure he only sees me as a friend.
あの人はきっと私だけを友達にしているに違いない。
Don't overthink this.
でたらめを考えてはいけない。
Let's give this post a like.
いいねを押す
Don't you enjoy
あなたは飲むのが好きではありません
coriander flavored beverages?
パクチー味の飲み物ですか
What are you trying to say?
何が言いたいの
Since you are Su Chengcheng's friend,
あなたが蘇澄の友人である以上
you should stay in the friend zone.
あなたは友達の席にいて
Chengcheng,
クリアー
did you finish retrieving the equipment?
設備を取りに行ってきましたか。
When are you heading back to the dorm?
いつ寮に帰りますか。
Moreover, did Gu Chen contact you?
まだ顧晨から連絡がありますか。
I reckon he's going to
私は彼がこの2，3日の間に
confess his feelings to you in two days.
きっとあなたに告白する
You'd better prepare for that.
覚悟してくれ
Chengcheng.
クリアー
Let me help you.
私が運んであげましょう
This is too heavy.
これは重すぎる
Chengcheng, do you have a moment?
澄澄空いてる？
I have something to tell you.
私はあなたに言いたいことがあります
I'm busy at the moment. I need to
私は暇がありません。私は物を持っています。
return the stuff to the laboratory.
実験室にも行く
I'm all tied up.
私はとても忙しい
Well, then, what about tonight?
じゃ、今晩は暇ですか。
The night's already taken, too.
今夜も暇がない
OK, it's alright.
それはいい
I'll tell you another day.
またお話しします
Then it would be better if you tell me tonight.
じゃ、今晩言ってください。
OK.
よし
Let's meet at the garden at nine.
じゃあ9時に庭で会おう
The garden?
小庭
Why are you here?
どうして来たの？
As soon as I saw you borrow the card from Zhang Li,
張力とカードを借りているのを見た
I knew something was off.
問題があると思った
Now you even left the door unlocked.
今はドアが閉まっている
You are so confident about not being caught, aren't you?
発見されることを恐れていない
What's the matter?
何ですか
Du asked me to talk some sense into you.
杜さんは私に忠告させてくれた
If that's the case, you can go back now.
じゃあ帰ってもいいよ
I figured that you wouldn't listen.
君は忠告を聞かないだろうと推測した
If you did, then you wouldn't be Xiao Yuhe.
忠告を聞くとショー川ではない
Don't beat around the bush, get to the point.
話があったら直接に話す
The development of Musk needs the knowledge of
マースクの開発には
algorithm,
アルゴリズム
psychology,
心理学
mechanics,
機械
all those subjects.
多方面の学科
Even if you are a prodigy,
たとえあなたが天才であっても
don't you realize
でもあなたは
it would be
誰も助けてくれない
too difficult to complete
あなた一人で
without any help?
あなたはできますか。
I already acknowledge all these problems
あなたの言っているこれらの問題
you mentioned,
私は知っている
and I can solve them.
そして私はすべて解決することができます
I've already fed Musk
マースクは私に餌をやらせた
plenty of data.
多くのデータが
It's in the
もう着いた
reinforcement learning stage.
強化学習の段階
There's no need to worry.
心配しないで
Everything's fine.
問題ありません
You know for yourself that
あなた自身も知っている
Musk needs a large amount of
マスクには大量の
data on human emotional representations
人体感情特徴のデータ
in order to accurately correspond to
的確に対応できる
the mapping relationship of
外的表象
external appearances
内在的感情的特徴の
and internal emotional characteristics.
関係のマッピング
Who's its current learning sample?
それは今サンプルを勉強しているのは誰ですか。
Who does it interact with every day?
毎日誰とやり取りしているのか
It's only you, right?
あなただけかな
You set Musk
マースクの位置付け
as an
は、
emotional companion robot.
感情付き添い型ロボット
But you yourself
でもあなた自身は
are a person with avoidant attachment style.
回避型愛着人格
Do you think you can train it well?
あなたはそれをよく訓練していると思いますか。
I know I am
私は自分が
a person with avoidant attachment style.
回避型愛着人格
It's hard for me to be aware
気づきにくい
of my true feelings,
自分の実感
and it's even harder to directly express
直接表現するのは難しい
my feelings,
自分の気持ち
which results in contrasting
行動と考えを引き起こす
behaviors and thoughts.
まったく違う
If someone
相手が
makes me feel stressful,
ストレスを感じさせてくれる
I'll instinctively choose to avoid them.
本能的に回避を選ぶ
This will indeed become
これは確かにマースクになれる
the greatest obstacle of Musk's training.
最大の訓練障害
But I'll overcome it.
でも私はそれを克服します
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河
you've changed.
あなたは変わった
Did Du tell you
杜さんはあなたに言いました。
about the lab?
実験室のことですか
What's the matter?
何だよ
Our school hosts an assessment
私たちの学校は3年ごとに
every three years.
すべて1回の評価があります
This year is when it takes place.
ちょうど今年になりました
Our lab
実験室はどこだ?
has been doing basic research
ここ数年
these recent years,
基礎研究を続けている
and we haven't reached much of an achievement.
何の成果もない
So if we cannot
だからもし今年
pass the assessment this year,
評価が通らない
our lab
我々の実験室.
might exist no more.
ないかもしれない
What do you mean our lab might exist no more?
実験室がなくなったとは
It might get relegated,
降格です
then split and merged with other labs.
分割と統合
Du's been distressed lately,
杜さんは最近ずっと焦っている
but he doesn't want us to feel pressured,
でも彼は私たちにストレスを与えたくなかった
so he said nothing about it.
だからずっと外には言わなかった
I know Musk
マースクを知ってる
means a lot to you.
あなたにとって大きな意味がある
I'm not Du,
私は杜さんではありません
I think it's perfectly fine
あなたは自分のやりたいことをします
for you to do what you want to do.
全然大丈夫だと思います
But I also want you to know that
でも私もあなたに知ってほしい
you are a member of our lab.
あなたは実験室の一員です
You must carry the responsibility
君の責任だ
assigned to you.
担がなければならない
I understand.
わかりました
You can head back now.
先に帰ってください
Thank you.
ありがとう
I'll lock the door for you.
ドアに鍵をかけた
How about it?
どうですか
Am I right?
私の言うとおりでしょう
Gu Chen and Xiao Yuhe
顧晨と肖宇河
both like you.
全部好きだよ
What do you think?
あなたはどう思いますか。
I don't know.
知らなかった
Do you like Gu Chen?
朝を見るのは好きですか。
No.
いやだ
How about Xiao Yuhe?
あなたはショーが好きですか。
You still like him?
君はまだ彼のことが好きだよ。
At the beginning,
実は最初に
I just thought he's handsome.
私は彼がかっこいいと思っています
Hotheadedly,
頭が熱くなると
I confessed my feelings to him.
彼に告白した
After the love experiment
恋愛実験の後
I felt exasperated.
私はとても怒っています
I made up my mind
自分で決心する
never to make a fool of myself again,
これ以上自分で多情なことをしてはいけない。
and never to have anything to do
この人とは
with this person again.
少し関係がある
But then a lot of things happened,
でもその後いろいろあって
and I got to know
私に一つ見せてくれました
a different aspect of him.
違う彼
Then I
そして私は
truly fell in love with him.
本当に好きになって
He even treated me very well,
彼は私にも親切だった
which made me feel that
感じさせて
maybe he,
彼はたぶん
more or less,
どのくらい
also has a little bit of
ほんの少しだけ
a crush on me.
私を好きになって
It turned out that it's my own wishful thinking again.
そして私はまた片思いをしました
I was wrong again.
私はまた間違っています
He always makes me think
彼はいつも私に感じさせた
that I'm a fool.
自分はとても愚かな人だ
that I'm not a person who's worth
価値がない
being loved.
愛される人
I hate to feel this way.
私はこの感じが大嫌いです
You're wrong.
違うよ
Why do you always think for him?
どうしていつも彼のことを考えているのですか。
You cannot deny yourself
他人のせいにしてはいけない
just because of someone else.
自分を否定するんだよ
Right?
正しいかどうか
No matter what Xiao Yuhe thinks,
ショウハがどう考えても
we all like you,
みんな大好きだよ
and you are not a fool at all.
あなたは少しも愚かではありません
There, there.
よしよしよし
Well,
その
what about Gu Chen?
顧晨のところはどうするつもりですか。
You're gonna make it clear to him?
彼にはっきり言いなさい
I'll make it clear to him.
私は彼にはっきり言いに行きます
OK.
よし
Chengcheng.
クリアー
Gu Chen.
顧晨
I bought you bubble tea.
ミルクティーを買ってあげました
It's your favorite flavor.
あなたの大好きな味
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Why don't you look at the screen?
スクリーンを見てみろ
What's worth looking at?
何か面白いことがありますか。
The drone. Where's the drone?
飛行機はどこだ?
Take a look, are these two
これを見てごらん
Su Chengcheng and Gu Chen?
蘇澄澄と朝を見よう
I finally understand.
私はやっとわかった
I said a lot last time
私はこの前あなたにそんなにたくさん言った
and nothing registered with you.
君は一言も聞き入れなかった
Xiao Yuhe.
肖宇河
It's not that I'm against you
私はあなたを止めるのではありません
participating in the competition,
試合に出る
I'm not a...
私もそうではありません
ruthless person either.
不人情な人
I also grew up...
私も
from your age.
あなたはこの年に来ました
I understand the passion
私はあなたの年齢を知っています
young people at your age possess
若者がやりたいことがある
when they want to do something.
その情熱は
But it really
でも今はタイミングよ
is not the right time.
本当に未熟だった
What happened to you
先年
years ago
あなたのそのこと
was just barely suppressed,
やっとのことでおさえた
and you want to do it again.
またやるのか
Aren't you deliberately
君はわざとじゃない
putting yourself in danger?
波頭に衝突か
Right?
正しいかどうか
Moreover,
しかも
our laboratory is
私たちの実験室の圧力よ
under great pressure as well.
今でも大きい
A lot of pairs of eyes
あんなにたくさんの目
are on us.
見つめてるよ
Our research paper
我々の論文
was rejected, again.
また戻ってきた
If it continues this way,
このまま発展していくには
our laboratory's funding
すべての資金
will be withdrawn entirely.
それでは実験室から撤収します
Your phone just won't stop, right?
あなたの携帯を見てください。
It's been buzzing the entire time.
ブンブンいう
Take a look at it.
見てみろ
See.
ほら
Are these two Chengcheng
これは澄澄さんの妹ではありませんか。
and Gu Chen?
顧晨と
They are at the garden,
彼らは小さな庭にいます
talking and laughing all by themselves.
一人っ子で寡婦でしゃべったり笑ったりする
Are you sure you are not going to take a look?
見に行かないのか?
You can leave. Just go.
行ってらっしゃい、行ってらっしゃい
Please take good care of
あなたは自分のことを
your own business.
処理して
I see that
私は見ます
our laboratory
私のこの実験室は
really can't count on you.
私は本当にあなたを指すことができません
Prof. Du,
杜先生
please do not worry,
ご安心ください
I'll put my heart
このプロジェクト
in this project.
私はきっとちゃんとします
But I have my own insistence.
でも私には私なりのこだわりがある
I asked you to come here today
今日はあなたを呼んでいます
is mainly because of
主に用事がある
one thing I wanted to tell you.
あなたに伝えたい
-I like Senior Xixi... -I have a crush on someone else.
私は西渓さんが好きです。
What did you say?
何て言った?
You like Senior Xixi?
あなたは西渓の先輩が好きです。
You know about how Senior Xixi is.
西渓さんも知っていますか。
She's not a person who likes
彼女はいつも
to socialize,
あまり人と接触しない
so it's even harder to chase after her.
彼女を追うのは言うまでもない
I've never told her,
私はずっと彼女に言ったことがない
but
しかし
you are in the same group
今あなたと彼女は
as her,
グループ内に
so, I want to...
だから私は
I got it.
わかりました
Thanks.
ありがとうございます
Are you heading back to the dorm?
寮に帰りますか。
I'm going to the library,
ちょうど図書館に行きました。
I can give you a lift.
私はあなたを乗せてもいいです。
I'm good.
いいえ
I'll wait here for...
私はここで待っています
I mean,
私は人と約束した
I have something else to do later.
あとでちょっと用事がある
Well,
あの
I'll wait here a bit,
私はここでしばらく待っています。
you go ahead.
先に帰ってください
OK, then bye.
はい、行ってきます
Gu Chen,
顧晨
why did you
あなたのモーメンツ
block me on Moments?
どうして私を遮るの
Why did I block you?
あなたを隠す
I didn't.
ないよ
You did.
ありますよ
Tell me which post?
どれを言ってるんだ?
The one with a quotation from Shen Congwen.
沈従文のあれだ
Here's the thing.
そうです
When I posted something on my Moments,
私はモーメンツを送信します
my relatives always
親戚が来る
asked questions and it's annoying,
あれこれ聞くのは煩わしい
so I moved them
だから私は親戚たちを
into a group and blocked them.
グループを引いてブロックした
M-My aunt's also named Su Chengcheng,
私の叔母も蘇澄澄と申します
and I might have made a mistake.
私は間違って引いたようです
Take a look. Take a look.
見てごらん
It's true, see?
本当に見て
My aunt really is named Su Chengcheng.
私の二番目のおばさんは本当に蘇澄澄と呼ばれています。
My aunt's name is Su Chengcheng.
私の二番目のおばさんは蘇澄澄と申します。
Fine, you win.
私はほんとうに悔しい。
Hurry up and unblock me.
早く引き出してくれ
I know. I know.
わかったわかった
OK.
よし
I'm removing you from the group right now.
今すぐ引き戻してあげる
-Later, aunt. -Off you go.
私は2番目のおばさんを離れました
-Go. Bye. -I'm leaving.
行こうさよなら
Bye. Bye.
さようなら
See you.
さようなら。
I almost made a fool of myself again.
もう少しでまた自業自得になるところだった
That's a close call.
危ない
Look.
見て見て
What a tragedy.
惨めだ
Can you stop following me?
ついてこないでくれませんか。
I'll send you back.
私はあなたを送り返します
You're here to watch me make a fool of myself, right?
あなたが来たのは私の恥を見に来たのでしょう
Then you can watch it all you want.
見てみろ
Are you happy?
楽しかったですか
Dry yourself with this.
拭きましょう
Your hair's all wet.
髪がすっかりぬれてしまった
Who asked you to pity me?
誰が私をかわいそうにしたの?
Who asked you to mind my business?
誰が私のことを気にしたの?
Who asked you to be
誰が君を馬鹿にしたんだ?
a hypocrite?
ここでいい人になろう
Who asked you to transfer me
誰が私を行かせたの?
to Senior Xixi's group?
西渓の先輩のところ
Who asked you to let me stay in the lab?
誰が私を実験室に残したの?
Why are you being so unreasonable
君はどうしてそんなにわけがわからないのか。
and annoying?
こんなにいらいらさせるのか
I'm not wearing your clothes.
私はあなたの服を着ない
It's...
これは
the one I bought for him.
私が彼に買ってあげたもの
So he didn't throw it away.
彼は捨てなかったのか
Put this on
きちんと着替える
and hurry back.
急いで帰る
Don't catch a cold.
風邪を引かないで
Drink something warm.
熱いのを飲んで
It's none of your business.
あなたには関係ない
Drink it.
飲んで
What are you gonna do this time?
何してるの?
Drink my sorrows away.
酒で憂さを紛らす
Cheers, my friend.
乾杯しよう友達
Bring up your glasses.
グラスを上げろ
Friends.
友人たち
Youth is brief.
青春は短い
Let's have another bottle again.
もう一本ください
Su Chengcheng.
スーザン
The gate is over there.
ゲートはあちらです
We should head back now.
もう帰らないと
Where did I go?
私はどこへ行きましたか。
I'm at home.
私は私の家に着いた
I'm at home and I'm gonna sleep.
家に着いたら寝るよ
You're drunk.
酔っ払ったな
Let me take you back.
私はあなたを送り返します
Nope.
いやだ
If you don't head back now,
もう帰らないで
the dorm's gonna close.
寮は閉まった
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河
do you know how much
あなたは私があなたのために
I've devoted to you?
いくら払ったの？
Because of you,
私はあなたのために
I spent the money
私は私を
I had saved up for an electric bicycle.
電気自動車を買うお金は全部使ってしまった
Do you know how hard it is
あなたは私がそのお金を貯めていることを知っています
for me to save up that amount of money?
どのくらい難しいですか。
I saved for over six months.
私は半年ほど貯金しました。
Do you know how many
私が記入したことを知っていますか。
surveys I completed,
アンケート
and how many times I became the practice partner with someone
何度練習のお供をしたことか
to save up that small amount of money?
稼いだだけの金か
Don't cry.
泣くなよ
Really, I worked so hard.
本当に私はとても苦労します
I worked hard to buy you a piece of clothing,
お金を稼いで服を買ってあげる
and you threw it away.
あなたはそれを捨てました
What are you laughing about?
何笑ってるの？
Am I ridiculous?
おかしいですか
No.
なし
OK, you're drunk.
いいわいいわ酔っ払って
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
明日またお話しします
Don't say tomorrow to me.
明日のことは言わないで
I don't want to hear it.
明日は言いたくない
Tomorrow I need to
明日はまた
ride my bicycle.
私の自転車に乗って
The chain of my bicycle
私の自転車
always falls off.
それはいつも鎖を落としている
I have to place it back in place everyday.
私は毎日それにチェーンをつけます
My hands are permeated with the smell of engine oil.
私の手には油の匂いがします
Really. They still stink
本当に今もあるのね
with engine oil.
オイルの匂いだ
Have a sniff.
聞いてごらん
Really.
本当に
Don't cry.
泣くな泣くな
My hands smell like engine oil.
オイルの匂いだ
OK, OK. Let's walk normally.
いいこともいいこともいいこともいいこともいいこともある
Watch your step.
転ばないで
I'm not gonna fall over.
私は転ばないわ
I'm good at walking.
私はよく歩いた
Watch me.
私が行ってあげましょう
Am I good at walking?
よく歩いたね
Yes, not only walking,
道がいいだけでなく
you are good at everything,
君はどこでもいい
OK?
いいですか
What am I good at?
私はどこがいいですか。
Why so sudden?
突然ですか
Let me think.
考えてみよう
You
あなた
have good skills in execution and action.
実行能力が高く行動能力が良い
I've learned how to catch lab rats.
私はマウスを捕まえることを覚えました
That's not what I mean.
そういう意味じゃない
You are happy every day.
あなたは毎日楽しいですね
You are always in a good mood, right?
気持ちがいいでしょう
What else? Crying all day?
そうでなければ毎日泣いている
How about this?
それでは
Well,
あなたは？
Jianming likes you,
建明はあなたが好きです
which means you are a good person.
あなたの良い人を証明します
What's the point of Jianming liking me?
建明は私が好きで何の役にも立たない
You don't like me.
あなたも私のことが好きではありません。
Who says I don't like you?
私はあなたが好きではないと誰が言ったのですか。
Let's go.
行ってらっしゃい
We're here.
着きました
You should hurry up and get upstairs.
急いで上がりましょう
It's almost time for the curfew.
さもないと門限時間になる
What for?
何でだよ
Why do I have to do
何で俺に何をさせたんだ?
whatever you said?
何をするんだよ
Why do I have to listen to you?
どうして君の言うことを聞くんだ
You are drunk. Get upstairs already.
飲みすぎだ早く上に行け
Lemme tell you something, Xiao Yuhe.
ショー宇河教えてあげる
Don't you think you can do whatever you like to me
私があなたのことが好きだと頼んではいけません。
just because I have a crush on you.
私のことを好きなようにしてください
Listen,
教えてあげる
I was over you a long time ago,
私はとっくにあなたが好きではありません
to tell you the truth.
私はあなたに本当のことを言いましょう。
To me,
あなたは私にとって
you are like this.
これのように
The air.
くうき
Do you understand, the air?
空気を知っていますか。
Like a bottle of air.
空気のように
That's enough.
大差ないでしょう
Are your roommates upstairs?
あなたのルームメイトはいますか。
How about asking them to pick you up?
彼女たちを迎えに行かせないと
You don't believe me, do you?
信じないでしょ
I'll prove it to you!
あなたは私があなたに証明することを信じないでください
See?
ほら
Even if I'm this close to you,
こんなに近くにいても
I'm...
私はすべて
Am I blushing?
私は顔が赤くなったのではないでしょうか。
There are many reasons to cause a blushing face.
顔が赤くなる原因はたくさんある
Blushing...
顔が赤くなる
The causes of blushing
顔が赤くなる原因になる
are plenty.
いろいろあります
A person with high blood pressure
高血圧の人
will have an enlarged heart
心臓が拡大するからです
and increased myocardial contraction rate,
心筋収縮率の増加
causing...
もたらす
Blood vessels in the head to expand and become congested.
頭部血管拡張充血
Yes.
はい
Blood vessel dilation in the brain
脳血管拡張もあります
can also cause blushing.
顔を赤らめる
In addition,
さらに
menopausal women
更年期の女性
also blush
体内にエストロゲンが少なくなったので
because of the decrease in estrogen.
彼女も顔が赤くなるだろう
So it cannot prove that I have a crush on you.
だから私があなたを好きだと証明することはできません
Let me try again.
もう一度やってみる
See?
ほら
Even if I hug you like this,
私はあなたを抱いていても
I also...
私も
My heart is racing.
私はドキドキしていますね
There are various causes
心拍数が速くなる原因
of the acceleration of heart rate.
いろいろあります
Intense exercise,
激しい運動の後
excessive mental stress,
ストレスがたまる
and hyperthyroidism
甲状腺機能亢進
can all result in heart racing.
ときめきすぎて
So it's not because
だから私もそうではありません
I have a crush on you.
あなたが好きだから
Don't overthink it.
考えすぎないで
You don't believe me?
信じないよ
No,
だめだ
I can't do this.
私はできません